ashworthcollege.edu 2019-02-15

# Privacy Policy - Ashworth College

We recognize the importance of protecting your privacy and the information that you share with us. Our Privacy Policy was developed as an extension of our commitment to combine the highest-quality products and services with the highest level of integrity. It is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect, use, and safeguard the personal information you provide and to help you make informed decisions when using our site, products, and services. This Privacy Policy will be continually assessed against new technologies, business practices, and our visitor’s and students’ needs.

## Collection of information

We collect personally identifiable information you voluntarily choose to disclose and aggregate information that is automatically collected when you visit the website. The information we collect from you will vary depending on how you choose to contact us. If you contact us via email or submit an online request for information, we will collect the information that you provide to us in your email message or request, including your name, contact information, email address, and any questions or comments that you may submit.

We use third-party tools that capture information about how users interact with our site and what pages they visit. The data we collect from these tools are used internally to better understand and support our users. We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our behalf. These companies may employ cookies and action tags (also known as single pixel gifs or web beacons) to measure advertising effectiveness. Any information that these third parties collect via cookies and action tags is completely anonymous.

## Use of information

Your personal information is used to process your request for program information and help match your interests with the training you seek. We may store your information and send you updates on your program and our school. We also use personal information for purposes of administering our business activities, providing customer service, and making other products and services available to our students and prospective students. Occasionally, we may also use the information we collect to notify you about important changes to the website, new services, and special offers we think you will find valuable.

## Regulatory and legal

Ashworth College adheres to state and federal laws and regulations, as well as accreditation requirements. Therefore, your information may be shared with a regulatory and/or accrediting agency.

## Business partners

Ashworth College works collaboratively with organizations to assist with certification, licensure, support for employment, and additional educational support. Personal information may be shared with a partnering organization.

In the general course of conducting business, Ashworth College may share your information with organizations to perform certain services. These services may include postal carriers, customer service, and marketing analysis. If a service provider has access to your personal information to perform their duties, they are strictly forbidden to use or share your information for any other purpose.

## Financial agencies

Ashworth College may provide financial outstanding balances to a collection agency. For more information, please see the [Catalog](https://www.ashworthcollege.edu/admissions/academic-catalog/) for the Collections Policy. The collection agency will work with students to resolve any outstanding balance. Collection agencies may report outstanding balances to one or more credit bureaus.

## FERPA compliance

Ashworth College’s policy regarding confidentiality is in keeping with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) and affords student certain rights with respect to their education records. This includes the following:

  1. The right to inspect and review the student's education records within 45 days of the day Ashworth College receives a request for access
  2. The right to request the amendment of the student's education records that the student believes are inaccurate
  3. The right to consent to disclosures of personally identifiable information contained in the student's education records, except to the extent that FERPA authorizes disclosure without consent. One exception which permits disclosure without consent is disclosure to school officials with legitimate educational interests. School officials are individuals or entities working for, or on the behalf of, the educational institution. A school official has a legitimate educational interest if the official needs to review an education record in order to fulfill his or her professional responsibility. As allowed within FERPA guidelines, Ashworth College may disclose education records without consent to officials of another school, upon request, in which a student seeks or intends to enroll.
  4. The right to file a complaint with the US Department of Education concerning alleged failure by Ashworth College to comply with the requirements of FERPA. At its discretion, Ashworth College may provide Directory Information in accordance with the provisions of the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act. Directory Information is defined as that information which would not generally be considered harmful or an invasion of privacy if disclosed. Students may withhold Directory Information by notifying the Registrar in writing. Please note that such withholding requests are binding for all information to all parties other than for those exceptions allowed under the Act.

For more information regarding Ashworth College FERPA compliance, please review the publically available institutional Catalog located here: [Catalog](https://www.ashworthcollege.edu/admissions/academic-catalog/).

## Children’s privacy

Persons under the age of 18 years of age, and who have not been emancipated, cannot enroll into the College or High School without a parent or guardian’s signature. For a student who is under the age of 18 years, all rights regarding education records are given to the student’s parent or guardian.

## Your choice

When we obtain personal information from you, we will provide you with the opportunity to opt out of any third-party disclosure of that information or its use in ways unrelated to the operation of the website. If you later decide to opt out of such disclosures, you may do so by contacting us at the following address:

**Ashworth College**  
Attn: Marketing Manager   
6625 The Corners Parkway  
Suite 500   
Norcross, Georgia 30092   
770-729-8400  
FAX 770-729-9294

## Access to your information

Maintaining information that is current, accurate, and complete allows us to make our website more useful and to provide our students and prospective students with better service. To that end, we encourage you to update your information from time to time. To review the information that we have concerning you and your use of this website, please contact us at the address or phone number set forth above.

## Data retention

Ashworth College retains your information in order to evaluate institutional effectiveness. Your information is secured indefinitely to fulfill state, accreditor, legal and other regulatory requirements.

## Security

We use industry-standard security measures to protect any personal information you may provide to us. However, we cannot guarantee that your submissions to our website, any content residing on our servers, or any transmissions from our server will be completely secure. The Student Portal and online exams can only be accessed with a valid student username and password. You are responsible for keeping your login information secret and confidential and for notifying us if you believe that your student login information has been stolen or might otherwise be misused.

## Updates to this privacy policy

As our understanding and application of privacy requirements evolve, it may be necessary to update this privacy policy. By your continuing use of this website, as a student or non-student, you accept the latest version of this policy. If you do not agree with this policy, discontinue using the website and contact Ashworth College by mail, email or phone:

**Ashworth College**  
Attn: DPO   
6625 The Corners Parkway  
Suite 500   
Norcross, Georgia 30092
